unitedfoodbank.org 2017-10-04

# Privacy Policy - United Food Bank

**UNITED FOOD BANK**

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Effective October 30, 2015**

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

United Food Bank (hereinafter “UFB”) hereby acknowledges and ascribes to the Association of Fundraising Professionals “ _Donor Bill of Rights_ ” and declares its commitment to protect the privacy and confidentiality of individuals who browse or engage in any activity on this website.

The following **_Privacy Policy_** applies to any and all information provided to and received by UFB, both online and offline, on any Platform, (“ _Platform_ ” includes UFB’s website, mobile apps, and social media), as well as to any electronic, written, or oral communications.  This **_Privacy Policy_** applies to any and all information that may be provided directly to UFB or indirectly to Third-Party Service Providers and Advertising Partners (hereinafter “Partners”) on and through this website. This **_Privacy Policy_** will also define the type and scope of any and all information collected and submitted through this website.

_**UFB does not rent, sell, or exchange donor information with any third-party.**_

**The Information We Collect**

On this website, individuals may make financial contributions, order products, request information, search or register to receive materials and will be asked to voluntarily provide **_Personal Information_** which may include: Name, Mailing Address, Email Address, Telephone Number, Credit Card/Debit Card Information, **_Non-Personal Information_** and **_Other Information_** required to acknowledge tribute gifts, request information, volunteer services, or to register and sign-up for events and other activities.

**Definitions**

**Personal Information:   _“_** _Personal Information”_ is hereby defined as any information that identifies or could be used to specifically identify a natural person.  Personal Information does not include information about corporate entities or information that is encoded, aggregated or anonymized, or that may already reside in the public domain.

**Non-Personal Information:** _“Non-Personal Information”_ is hereby defined as any technical information that cannot be used to specifically identify a natural person which is automatically collected upon access or use of this website.  Non-Personal Information may include:  IP Address, ISP, Browser, Operating System, Digital Device, and Language; Referring Page, Exit Page, and URL; Date, Time, Browsing History, Clicks, and Search Terms; Cookies1, JavaScript Tags, Web Beacons, Clear-Gifs, Pixel-Tags, Flash Cookies, and other objects.  Pixel tags enable UFB and its Partners to learn what brings browsers to this website.

**Other Information** :  “ _Other Information_ ” is hereby defined as Browsing Activity.  Browsing Activity may be shared with UFB Partners for the purpose of analyzing, managing, reporting, tailoring, and optimizing advertising that may appear on this website and elsewhere.

**Do Not Track (“DNT”** ).  “ _Do Not Track_ ” is a technology that enables users to opt out of tracking by websites they do not visit, including analytic services, advertising networks, and social platforms. DNT signals a user’s opt-out-preference with an HTTP header, a simple technology that is completely compatible with existing web applications.  UFB assumes no responsibility for responding to DNT web-browser signals.

**1** “Cookies” are small packets of digital-data stored on digital devices which “remember” information about web-browsing history.  “Session Cookies” expire once a web-browser is closed.  “Persistent Cookies” remain on digital devices until they are deleted.  UFB employs Java scripting to record and trigger a sequence of events which optimize a user’s experience on this website.  Individuals may elect to disable “Cookies” on their digital devices; however, this may affect the functionality of this website.  Consult your web-browser’s documentation to learn how to disable “Cookies”.

**Advertising Partners**

UFB may enter into agreements with Partners to deliver relevant, user-targeted, non-intrusive advertising.  Partners will not be granted access to Personal Information; however, UFB may grant access to Non-Personal Information with Partners.  Partners maintain their own privacy policies which should be reviewed in connection with the use of this website.

Significant partners currently include, but are not limited to:

**Google Analytics**.  “ _Google Analytics_ ” is a web service provided by Google, Inc. (“ _Google_ ”).  Google places “Cookies” on digital devices to track internet usage and browsing history.  Non-Personal Information gathered by “Cookies” is transmitted and stored on Google servers in the United States.  Google collects information anonymously and aggregates this data to report on website activity, internet usage and trends.  Google may deliver this information to third-parties where required to do so by law or where such third-parties process information on Google’s behalf.

By using UFB’s website, you expressly consent to the processing and sharing of Non-Personal Information by Google in the manner and for the purposes stated above.   Individuals may opt-out of Google Analytics on their digital devices without affecting navigation of this website.  Consult Google and/or your browser’s documentation for information on how to do this.

**How We Use and Share the Information     **

UFB uses Personal, Non-Personal and Other Information to process donations, solicit feedback, and acquire information; to disseminate information about UFB activities, programs, services and to connect people to resources.  UFB may employ other Partners to perform various functions to provide technical support and customer service.  UFB may grant Partners access to Personal, Non-Personal, and Other Information required to perform such functions to the extent permitted by law:  (i) when required by law, court order, or other government or law enforcement authority or regulatory body; or (ii) whenever UFB believes that disclosing such information is necessary or advisable to protect the rights, property, or safety of UFB and others.  In an ongoing effort to better understand website usage, UFB may also aggregate and share information with Partners to improve, enhance, manage, and maintain this website and social media platforms.   This aggregate data does not identify individuals personally and may be shared with Partners to perform various functions for contracted services to the extent allowed by law.

**Accessing and Modifying Information and Communication Preferences**

Upon request, UFB may grant access to Personal Information that we and our Partners maintain.   Individuals may review and/or make changes to their Personal Information by contacting UFB.  In addition, individuals may also manage receipt of communications from UFB by clicking the “ _Unsubscribe_ ” link located on the bottom of UFB marketing e-mails or by requesting the same through this website.  UFB will employ every commercially reasonable step to process such requests in a timely manner.  However, it may not be possible to modify or completely remove information from our subscription databases in all circumstances.

**How We Protect the Information**

While UFB will employ every commercially reasonable step to protect Personal Information that is entered, stored, and transmitted by this website against loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, no security system is impenetrable.  UFB cannot guarantee the security of Personal Information from cyber-attack or interception on the Internet.  Information sent or received via E-mail from this website may not be secure and special care should be taken when deciding what information to send via E-mail.

**Important Notices to Non-U.S. Residents**

It is important to note that this website and servers are operated in the United States.  If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any Personal Information provided to us will be transferred to the United States.  You hereby and unconditionally consent to the transfer of such Personal Information in accordance with this **_Privacy Policy_**.   For questions regarding this **_Privacy Policy_** , please contact UFB as described in the “ _How to Contact Us_ ” section below.  We will investigate your question, respond to your inquiry, and attempt to address your privacy concerns.

**External Websites**

UFB’s website contains links to Partners and third-party websites.  UFB does not administer the privacy policies of such websites and is not responsible for the content and privacy policies of these websites.  Always review the privacy policy and terms of use when visiting other websites.

**Children**

UFB does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of thirteen (13) on this website.  If you are under the age of thirteen, please do not provide your Personal Information.  We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor children’s Internet usage to help enforce this provision of this **_Privacy Policy._** Please instruct children never to disclose Personal Information over the Internet without permission.  If you have reason to believe a child under the age of thirteen has disclosed Personal Information on this website, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete said information from our databases.

**Acceptance of Terms & Changes to this Privacy Policy**

By visiting UFB website, you agree to be bound by the terms of this **_Privacy Policy._**   Capitalized terms not specifically defined in this **_Privacy Policy_** shall have the meaning set forth in our **_Terms of Use_**.  This **_Privacy Policy_** is effective as of Friday, October 30, 2015.  UFB may change this **_Privacy Policy_** from time to time.  Please be aware that, to the extent permitted by law, use of Personal Information and Other Information is governed by the **_Privacy Policy_** in effect at the time we collect the information.  Please refer back to this **_Privacy Policy_** on a regular basis.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have questions about this **_Privacy Policy_** , or wish to opt out and no longer receive direct mail, e-mail, electronic or social media communications, please contact United Food Bank via: E-mail at [donations@unitedfoodbank.org](mailto:donations@unitedfoodbank.org) and place “PRIVACY POLICY” in the subject line of this e-mail; or by mailing a letter to Privacy Administrator, United Food Bank, 245 S. Nina Drive, Mesa Arizona 85210; or by calling United Food bank at (480) 926-4897, ext. 233.

– See more at: https://unitedfoodbank.org/privacy-policy/#sthash.e3GTwdPC.dpuf
